Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kaushalsahasrabuddhe-719581163 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

System Administration
Windows Server
Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Kaushal Sahasrabuddhe

Team Lead at LTI Mumbai | Windows |AWS-CSA | VMWARE Thane, Maharashtra, India

Summary

Completed Bsc (IT) form Mumbai University Certified as Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (70-640) and AWS Solution Architect .Total IT experience of 12 year. Currently working at Team lead position in LTI Mumbai.Working knowledge of multi platform technology tower's like Windows, VMWare & AWS.

Experience

LTI Mumbai Team Lead March 2019 - Present Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

BlazeClan Technologies Associate solution Architect March 2017 - Present Mumbai Area, India

- •Responsible for managing and maintaining the IT infrastructure for various Customers hosted on AWS (Amazon Web Services) and act as a SPOC for all assigned projects
- •AWS Based Provisioning –EC2,S3,IAM,Cloud Watch, SGs ,ELB,Lambda etc.
- •Configuration & Troubleshooting on windows servers 2008R2, 2012R2 which are running on EC2 instances.
- •Deploying hot fix and security patches on monthly basis for all windows servers running on AWS for all clients across the organization.
- •Configuration & Troubleshooting on various server roles like ADDS, windows failover cluster ,RD Gateway server, FTPS ,ADFS for single sign on etc.
- •Conducting vulnerability testing using AWS inspector services and there mitigation.
- •AWS setup and migration activities.
- •Securing the Environment as per the AWS CIS Foundation Framework .

Hitachi Payment Services Pvt. Ltd. Sr.Server Engineer September 2014 - March 2017 (2 years 7 months) Mumbai Area, India

- Responsible for managing and maintaining the IT Infrastructure for Hitachi Payments services.
- Lead team of 8 engineers in datacenter environment encompassing 50+ physical servers and 300+ VMs.
- Manage communication with internal clients and third party partners to track,
 resolve and escalate issues and open tickets.
- Configuration & Troubleshooting on windows 2003R2, 2008R2, 2012R2 server roles like File server, Wsus, DNS, DHCP, IIS.
- Installation, configuration and Hardening of OS and Application
- Deploying hot fix and security patches on monthly basis for all servers using Wsus servers.
- Closely monitor windows performance issues and taking necessary actions for closers.
- Handling various IIS related activities such as site deployment, certificate mapping & port binding.
- Troubleshooting Exchange 2007 issues related to mail flow/Queue, Antispam, non-delivery of mails for particular domain.
- Moderate knowledge of Handling NetApp storage E2700.
- VM's provisioning as per the requirements, coordinating with Business and application owners.
- Deploying update patches for ESXI servers.
- Working experience on virtual switches, and others tools like P2V, V2V.
- Hardware upgradetion such as memory upgradetion, HBA card installation, HDD replacement and Raid expansion etc.
- Creating batch file for schedule jobs such as deletion, copying, encryption etc.
- Second level Escalation for DCO, service providers, vendors and customers.
- Completed Symantec DLO application installation, testing & implementation across all location.
- Handling PCI audit related activities such as vulnerabilities closer for CDD, ASV, VA PT scan, providing evidence to auditors by coordinating with application owners etc.

NSE.iT Limited IT Executive April 2011 - September 2014 (3 years 6 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Project: NSE Collocation Data center

- •Managing NSE Collocation data center for 24*7/365 Support, Working in a shift.
- •Co-ordination and monitoring for Rack installation, Hygro meter installation and COLO DC infrastructure Requirements like PACs, Door stoppers, Blanking panels, surveillance systems etc.

consumption monitoring & other facilitation to visitors when they visit COLO DC.

- •Handling calls regarding TAP/TBT IPs, queries of members, general information, COLO announcements, COLO problems/incidents, follow-ups & timely escalate the call to respective internal team.
- •Co-ordination with internal team regarding TBT issue to Info feed team, TAP Latency/TAP disconnection/User logged off etc issues to IP Support team, Telnet / ping etc issue to Network team. Getting payment confirmation for TAP & TBT IP & software Approval from Membership department.
- •CRM ticket logging, updating and closure in case of incidents, queries, information, requests, problems. Updating Assets, escalation matrix, TAP & TBT IPs provided to respective Member.
- •Time to time escalating issues and problems like Ping flood smurf attack, ICMP traffic issue from their servers etc with members according to their escalation matrix and following up with them for the same.

Project: Power Exchange of India Limited

- •Providing complete Server and desktop support which includes software as well as hardware support to all users.
- •Configuring and Maintaining of user accounts on Active Directory.
- •Creating users, groups for specific department & Implementation of the NTFS permissions and security policies in Windows 2008 Server environment.
- •Configuring and Maintaining WSUS server for updating windows patches on clients machines.
- •Installation of PXIL Trading Application on the client machines using the Team viewer connection.
- •SPOC for all clients across PAN India for resolving and troubleshooting of the issue related to the power trading application.

IT Engineer

July 2008 - April 2011 (2 years 10 months)

Mumbai Area, India

- •Responsible for providing complete desktop support which includes software as well as hardware support to all users. (No of users 500).
- •To add new users to the network, configure & troubleshoot their IT issues.
- •To ensure network connectivity throughout the facility through wireless or LAN.
- •Working as a System/Network Administrator Maintaining Cbay's High End production, Domain, DHCP and FTP servers which runs on Windows 2003 Server Operating System.
- •Keep in touch with various Vendors like IBM (Lenovo) and Dell for replacement of faulty parts in any of the Laptops and desktops.
- •Creating users, groups for specific department & Implementation of the NTFS permissions and security policies in Windows 2003 Server environment.
- •Software deployment through group policy.
- •Work experience on Virtualization Platform such as VM Ware .
- •Completed a project of conversion of physical machine to the Virtual Environment with the help of tools like P2V.
- •Work closely with other departments to ensure that IT service is delivered as per SLA.

Trimax Computer Pvt Ltd IT Engineer July 2007 - July 2008 (1 year 1 month) Mumbai Area, India

- •Troubleshooting of Desktops & Laptops regarding Hardware, software problems.
- •Managing and resolving issues related to email clients such as Outlook express, MS Outlook 2003/2007.
- •Ensure that all the systems antivirus program is properly updated
- Vendor management and maintaining inventory of IT related assets

Education

Mumbai University Mumbai

Bachelor of Information Technology, Information Technology (2004 - 2007)